Guide to the Paul S. Robinson Papers, 1932-1941
Duke University. University Archives
Paul S. Robinson papers 1932-1941
Duke University. University Archives
Robinson, Paul S.
0.5 linear feet Extent: 200 Items
Paul Robinson was an organist at the Duke University Chapel from 1932-1941. The collection includes programs for Chapel and Duke musical events, clippings, and other material related to the Duke Summer School Choir. It ranges in date from 1932-1941.
RL.01801
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Paul S. Robinson Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1980.
Biographical Note
Paul Robinson received a graduate degree in Organ Performance from the Curtis Institute in Philadelphia. He also received his M.A. in Sacred Music from New York City's School of Sacred Music in Union Theological Seminary, where he remained active in artists' courses. During the winters, he served as organist and choirmaster of the Beck Memorial Presbyterian Church, also in New York City. He worked as an organist at Duke from 1932-1941.
Collection Overview
Collection includes newspaper clippings about Robinson's organ recitals in the Duke University Chapel, as well as programs for organ and carillon recitals and Chapel worship services. Also includes miscellaneous programs for event sin the Chapel, and a booklet of photos, entitled "Campus Views." Includes program from what was probably the first organ recital in the Chapel on June 1, 1932. The collection ranges in date from 1932-1941.
Subject Headings
Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Duke University. Chapel -- Organs; Organists -- United States; Robinson, Paul S.
Related Material
News Service Biographical Files, 1960-2004
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Organ and Carillon Recital Programs, Organ Specifications, 1932-1940 (Box 1)
  - Organ Recital Programs, 1932 Summer
  - Programs for Duke University Chapel Worship Services, 1932, 1935-1941
  - Miscellaneous Material on Duke University Summer School Choir, 1936-1941
  - Carillon Recital Programs and Newspaper Clippings, 1932-1941
  - Newspaper Clippings Concerning Organ Recitals, 1932-1941
  - Organ Recital Programs, 1933 Summer
  - Programs for Miscellaneous Events in Duke University Chapel, 1932-1941 - includes booklet of photos - Campus Views, 1941
  - Organ Recital Programs, 1934-1941
  - Duke University Voice Recital Programs, Clippings, Reviews, 1939-1941